Finding Aid for Elizabeth Lemmer papers, 1969-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Elizabeth Lemmer papers 1969-1978
Lemmer, Elizabeth, collector.
1 linear foot.
851870 Aa 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan, right-to-life activist; collected newsletters, clippings, and other materials relating to the right-to-life movement
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was deposited by Elizabeth Lemmer (donor no. 5516 ) beginning in 1974. Additional material were received.
The collection is open to research.
Elizabeth Lemmer of Ann Arbor, Michigan was active in various pro-life, anti-abortion organizations beginning in the late 1960s.
The Elizabeth Lemmer papers consists of collected newsletters and printed material from Michigan Citizens for Life (later renamed Right-to-Life of Michigan) and the Michigan Right-to-Life Committee, a political action group organized to counter attempts to legalize abortion in 1972. In addition, the collection includes scattered correspondence and newspaper clippings regarding the issue of abortion.
Subjects:
Pro-life movement--Michigan.; Elections--Michigan--1972.; Michigan--Politics and government--1971-1980.; Michigan Right-to-Life Committee.; Right to Life of Michigan.; Women's rights--Michigan.; Women in politics--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
- Collected right-to-life materials
  - Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Citizens for Life-Conventions, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Right-to-Life Committee
    - Miscellaneous and printed material regarding abortion, 1971-1976 (Box 1)
    - Promotional and campaign literature, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - National Right-to-Life Convention (Detroit), 1973 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Grand Rapids Right-to-Life Committee) (Box 1)
    - 1974-1977 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings 1971-1978 and undated, 14 folders (Box 1)
  - Audio cassettes, undated, 1969, 1972, 4 cassette tapes (Box 1)